# Priyanka Sarkar

Associate (Data Science)

Contact: +91-9748252816

Email: 7priyankasarkar@gmail.com

Bengaluru,IN

# **Summary:**

Highly motivated and passionate Analytics Expert who is specialized in translating real world business challenges into Analytics Frameworks and delivers strategic recommendations back to the client. Has experience in delivering end to end Data Science Project from Ideation to Evaluation and Model Deployment involving complete Data Science Lifecycle with total work experience of 3 years & 2 months.

# **Skill Set:**

## **Tools/Languages:**

## • LANGUAGES:

- Languages: Python, SQL, ASP.NET
- Visualization Tools/Lib: Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Seaborn, Tableau, PowerBI.

#### • DATABASES:

MYSQL

#### • OTHERS:

- Microsoft Excel
- Microsoft Power Point
- ➤ JIRA

## **Technical Skill:**

# • MACHINE LEARNING:

- > Classification Algorithm: Logistic Regression, Decision Tree, Random Forest, K-NN, SVM.
- > Regression Algorithms: Linear Regression, Logistic Regression, SVR.
- Clustering Techniques: K-Means, Hierarchical.
- Dimensionality Reduction: PCA.

#### • TEXT ANALYTICS/NLP:

- ➤ TF-IDF.
- Sentiment Analysis.
- Sentiment Analysis of Product Feedback.

## • STATISTICAL ANALYTICS:

- ➤ EDA.
- Inferential Statistics.
- Hypothesis Test, T-Test, Z-Test.
- > ANOVA, ANCOVA.
- Outlier Detection, Inter-Quartile Ranges.
- Sampling Techniques, Box-plot.

# **Employment Details:**

### Cognizant (Associate-Data Science) [Feb 2019 ~ Present]

- Credibility Analysis of a new product (policy) launch- The problem was to estimate if a customer would opt for an
  enhancement in the policy which Manulife is about to launch in this feature or not. The basic idea was to automate the
  calling and product description process to each customer associated with them. Insights given in Tableau.
   Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models Random Forest, CART, Logistic Regression, Matplotlib, Seaborn.
- Clustering of Product Parameters- The problem was to identify the behavior of the buyers and predict their nature on the
  basis of the products they have previously bought from Nestle in order to create a strategy for the customers to make them
  buy different and similar products. Insights given in Tableau.
   Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models Clustering-K means, Hierarchal Clustering, Matplotlib, Seaborn.

**Deployment flow:** Data Ingestion > Data Manipulation > Exploratory Data Analysis > Statistical Model Building > Model Evaluation > Deployment.

Sentiment Analysis- The assignment was to evaluate customer's response towards products of a Hoffmen genre which was
achieved through judging the sentiment of comments and feedbacks of the product users in order to help the client to get a
better idea in launching a product similar to Hoffmen. Insights given in Tableau.
 Skills/Libraries: Python, Machine Learning Models - NLP, TextBlob, TF-IDF, Scikitlearn, Matplotlib, NLTK.

**Deployment flow:** Data Ingestion > Data Manipulation > Exploratory Data Analysis > Statistical Model Building > Model Evaluation > Deployment.

## Cognizant (Programmer Analyst) [Mar 2018 ~ Feb 2019]

- 1. Writing Dot Net codes for a merger project of ACE and CHUBB insurance.
- 2. Working on maintenance as a FE developer for applications for CHUBB.

Skills Used: ASP.Net, SQL.

# **Projects & Competitions Portfolio:**

## **Machine Learning & Statistics**

- > HR Attrition Detection using Random Forest, Decision Tree and Logistic Regression.
- > Cancer detection using different classification models by checking the properties malignant and benign in cells.
- > Credit Risk Analysis using Decision Tree.
- > House Price Prediction using Linear Regression.
- > Predict Diabetes of a user from medical report using Logistic regression.
- > Principal Component Analysis based on Cancer Diagnosis data.

## **Education:**

B.Tech (CSE), B.P.Poddar Institute of Management & Technology, Kolkata(2013 ~ 2017)

#### Certifications:

ASP.Net, Dot Net framework, Python, SQL

#### **Declaration:**

I hereby declare that the above mentioned information is correct up to my knowledge and I bear the responsibility for the correctness of the above mentioned particulars.